Guide to the Stanford University, Stanford Associates, Peter Bing Project Videorecordings
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Stanford Associates, Peter Bing project videorecordings
1993-1994
V0099
Stanford University. Stanford Associates.
1 Linear feet 14 videotapes
Source tapes and the edited version of a project honoring Peter Bing, recipient of the Stanford Associates' Degree of Uncommon Man Award in 1994. Includes interviews with Frank Brennan, Richard Lyman, John Freidenrich, Donald Kennedy, Linda Meier, Shauna Jackson, Tara VanDerveer, Sonja Henning, and Morris Doyle. The interview with VanDerveer includes footage of the Stanford women's basketball team practicing.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, 1995.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Peter Bing, a member of the Stanford class of 1955, has been an active supporter of Stanford University. He served on the Board of Trustees from 1970 to 1981, and 1986 to the present; was a member of the Haas Public Service Center Advisory Committee; and was one of four co-chairs of the Centennial Campaign.
Description of the Collection
Source tapes and the edited version of a project honoring Peter Bing, recipient of the Stanford Associates' Degree of Uncommon Man Award in 1994. Includes interviews with Frank Brennan, Richard Lyman, John Freidenrich, Donald Kennedy, Linda Meier, Shauna Jackson, Tara VanDerveer, Sonja Henning, and Morris Doyle. The interview with VanDerveer includes footage of the Stanford women's basketball team practicing.
Access Terms
Bing, Peter.; Brennan, Frank.; Doyle, Morris.; Freidenrich, John.; Henning, Sonja.; Jackson, Shauna.; Kennedy, Donald, 1931-; Lyman, Richard W., 1923-2012.; Meier, Linda.; Stanford University. Department of Athletics.; Stanford University. Stanford Associates.; VanDerveer, Tara; Sports for women.
Collection Contents
- Beta Source Tapes
  - Reel 1, Brennan and Lyman, 10/8/1993 (Box 2)
  - Reel 1A, Sonja Henning; and Morris Doyle, 11/8/1993; 12/7/93 (Box 2)
  - Reel 2, John Freidenrich, 10/8/1993 (Box 2)
  - Reel 3, Kennedy, Bloem, Swezy, 10/15/1993 (Box 2)
  - Reel 4, Linda Meier and Shawna Jackson, 11/4/1993 (Box 2)
  - Reel 5, Tara VanDerveer and Shawna Jackson, 11/11/1993 (Box 2)
- VHS window dubs
  - Brennan/Lyman/Freidenrich (beta reels 1 and 2), 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Sonja Henning and Morris Doyle (beta reel 1A), 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
- Beta tapes
  - "Peter Bing", IMC original, Tape 1, 1/7/1994 (Box 2)
  - "Peter Bing", IMC original, Tape 2, 1/7/1994 (Box 2)
- VHS window dub
  - "Peter Bing", IMC, 1/7/1994; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
- Digital Video
  - Submaster, Peter Bing, 1/11/1994 (Box 2)